Nelson Bruno Andrés Moreno Cabañas

Data Scientist — Machine Learning Engineer

+56 997200464 | nelson.moreno.cabanas@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/nelson-moreno-cabanas | github.com/Bruno-Moreno

SUMMARY

Data Scientist with over 3 years of experience building end-to-end data science projects across different industries. My mathematical background enables me to solve technical problems with high precision and attention to detail. My experience among various industries has provided me with a broad understanding of different collaboration strategies and effective communication skills.

I am seeking a challenging job with several growth opportunities. I am always eager to learn and not afraid to step out of my comfort zone.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, SQL, R

Developer Tools: Git, Docker, AWS, Snowflake, Airflow, Vertex AI **Libraries**: SciPy, Pandas, PySpark, Scikit-Learn, Tensorflow, PyTorch

Data Visualization: Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, Power BI

EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist Sep. 2023 – Current

Rappi | Rappicard by Itaú - Digital Credit Card

Santiago, Chile

- Implemented a segmentation model that enabled tracking of client's activity, behavior, satisfaction and churn propensity. The retention actions across different segments resulted in a churn rate decrease and a NPS improvement.
- Worked on an acquisition model for Rappi's top users and successfully increased 2x the number of contracts in that group.
- Tested new communication strategies with the marketing team and measured their statistical effectiveness. This AB testing lead to user's personalization of communications.
- Developed and monitored a generative AI model designed to classify NPS survey responses for easier analysis.
- Created ETL processes to address business needs using Airflow, delivering processed data to the BI team for their reports.

Data Scientist Aug 2022 - Sep 2023

Consorcio - Bank and Insurance Company

Santiago, Chile

- Successfully created customer propensity models for all Consorcio's products, resulting in a significant reduction in the cost of acquisition. I developed a product churn prediction model that achieved a 5% reduction in churn rate every month, as well as a risk measurement model that improved the previous model AUC by 10pp.
- MLOps practices were implemented in collaboration with AWS for monitoring and maintaining machine learning models using Sagemaker Studio. These practices are now implemented through the entire Data & Analytics area.
- Designed a chatbot capable of reading information from multiple sources to assist our clients on Consorcio's
 products. This chatbot increased the NPS score among a group of clients and reduced the workload of the customer
 service team.
- Led a team of four people during transitional periods in the area, ensuring that each person's projects continued to develop without interruption.

Data Scientist Dec 2021 - Aug 2022

IC Innovations - CHASKi: Wearable sport device for athletes

Santiago, Chile

- Responsible for data processing and algorithm development for a wearable device designed to measure athlete's respiratory rates during exercise.
- Tested the algorithms against clinical experiments and achieved 92% accuracy in determining ventilatory thresholds.
- Created the first customized report delivered to athletes as the MVP of the product.

Data Science Intern Dec 2020 - Jan 2021

• Develop an anomaly detection, satisfy period monitoring and biomass estimation software for salmon in captivity using image processing and deep learning tools. This project enabled Alaya to enter the aquaculture market.

Data Analyst Intern

Dec 2019 - Feb 2020

Deloitte - Consulting, Financial Advisory, Risk Advisor

Santiago, Chile

• Provision estimation for banks according to the BASEL III manual.

EDUCATION

University of Chile

Santiago, Chile

Master's Degree, Data Science (Grade 6.7/7.0) Master's Thesis

2022 - 2023

University of Chile

Santiago, Chile

Bachelor's Degree, Mathematical Engineer (Grade 6.7/7.0)

2017 - 2023

ACADEMIC

Teacher Assistant - University of Chile

Lectures and content creation:

Machine Learning (1), Statistics (2), Linear Algebra (1), Ordinary Differential Equations (2), Calculus (1), Probabilities and Statistics (4).

CEIMAT Director - University of Chile

Director of the Mathematical Engineering Student Center at the Faculty of Physical and Mathematical Sciences.

LANGUAGES

English

Full professional proficiency

Spanish

Native

CERTIFICATIONS

Inspect Rich Documents with Gemini Multimodality and Multimodal RAG - Google

Issued Jan 2024

Generative AI Fundamentals - Google

Issued Jan 2024

Apache Airflow Fundamentals - Platzi

Issued Nov 2023

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner - Udemy

Issued Jan 2023

B2: Upper Independent - TOEFL ITP

Issued Jan 2019, Expires Jun 2021